<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">CC technical blog</title>
  <id>urn:uuid:3b553364-cf6e-3235-baa1-779d27c1a90b</id>
  <updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/" />
  <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <author>
    <name></name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/ajdavis/lektor-atom" version="0.3">Lektor Atom Plugin</generator>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-catalog-leverage-open-data-1/">
    <title type="text">CC Catalog: Leveraging Open Data and Open APIs</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:e24cc83b-b6fb-312b-b379-5aa16af58a16</id>
    <updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-catalog-leverage-open-data-1/" />
    <author>
      <name>sclachar</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is the first of a three part series about the underlying infrastructure for Creative Commons (CC) Catalog and the efforts to increase the volume and variety of creative works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog&quot;&gt;CC Catalog&lt;/a&gt; is to facilitate the discovery of openly licensed content, that proliferates the web. However, this is a challenging task and it requires a combination of techniques. The initial efforts to catalog the Commons began in 2016. The goal was to identify approximately &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/cc-search-developer-notes-and-reflection-418271194682&quot;&gt;1% of the estimated 1.4 billion works&lt;/a&gt;, by harnessing open repositories and open APIs to build a &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2017/02/07/new-cc-search/&quot;&gt;front door to the Commons&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, there has been an emphasis on including more content and discovering new platforms. While CC Catalog still leverages open data to achieve the above, we needed to develop the appropriate infrastructure to also routinely update the existing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of this infrastructure began in 2018, with the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://commoncrawl.org/&quot;&gt;Common Crawl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(computing)&quot;&gt;data pipeline&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Spark&lt;/a&gt; was used to streamline the processing of petabytes of web crawl data to identify all domains that link to a Creative Commons license. The first test of this strategy was successful and it was instrumental in increasing the number of images and added 13 new platforms for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2018/09/24/big-changes-for-cc-search-beta-updates-released-today/&quot;&gt;updates to CC Search beta&lt;/a&gt;. It also provided incremental updates to the catalog on a monthly basis. Even though Common Crawl corpus is an invaluable source, it requires us to develop a custom parser for each platform that we integrate. This has its merits, but presents a few challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_API&quot;&gt;Open APIs&lt;/a&gt; were explored and its purpose was not to replace the Common Crawl methodology but to augment it and hopefully increase the volume of data. This approach began with two platforms: 1) Flickr, since it its known to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.flickr.net/en/2019/03/08/update-on-creative-commons-licenses-and-in-memoriam-accounts/&quot;&gt;millions of CC license content&lt;/a&gt; and 2) Thingiverse. At the end of 2018, the exploratory efforts paid off and the catalog grew from 10 million images to over 260 million and the Flickr API was instrumental in achieving this. In early 2019, three new API providers were included: 1) Met Museum, 2) Cleveland Museum, and 3) Brooklyn Museum. This led to the development of our API &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extract,_transform,_load&quot;&gt;ETL data pipeline&lt;/a&gt; which is managed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://airflow.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Airflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we have over 305 million images from 25 providers, and we are still working to improve the data infrastructure and solidify our efforts for &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2017/02/07/new-cc-search/&quot;&gt;building a vibrant, usable Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/entries/cc-catalog-leverage-open-data-1/cc-catalog-growth.png&quot; alt=&quot;cc-catalog-img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above data is made available to &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;CC Search&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog-api&quot;&gt;CC Catalog API&lt;/a&gt;. However, all providers in the catalog are not immediately available in CC Search. Various preprocessing efforts are performed in the back-end by the CC Catalog API to determine which content is deemed ready for publishing. Also, platforms are subject to additional reviews and may be suppressed until that process has completed. Currently CC Search has 19 of the above providers, comprising over &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-search-out-of-beta/&quot;&gt;300 million images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal for 2019 is to increase the catalog to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;325 million images,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 providers, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add new content types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next post will discuss the details of the Common Crawl ETL Pipeline and how instrumental this corpus is for identifying potential providers and understanding how people are using the various CC license.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/meet-gsoc-2019-students/">
    <title type="text">Meet CC’s 2019 Google Summer of Code students</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:dba4248f-6d54-3bc7-a553-fae71da290e1</id>
    <updated>2019-05-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/meet-gsoc-2019-students/" />
    <author>
      <name>kgodey</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2019/03/04/cc-google-summer-of-code-2019/&quot;&gt;CC is participating in Google Summer of Code (GSoC)&lt;/a&gt;
 as a mentoring organization after a six year break from the program. We
 are excited to be hosting five phenomenal students (representing three 
continents) who will be working on CC tech projects full-time over the 
summer. Here they are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;students&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahmad Bilal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am Ahmad Bilal, a Computer Science undergrad from UET Lahore, 
      who likes computers, problems and using the former to solve the later. I
      am always excited about Open Source, and currently focused on Node.js, 
      Serverless, GraphQL, Cloud, Gatsby.js with React.js and WordPress. I 
      like organizing meetups, conferences and meeting new people. I view 
      working in GSoC with Creative Commons, one of the biggest opportunities 
      of my life. Cats are my weakness, and I am a sucker for well-engineered 
      cars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/creativecommons-wordpress-plugin&quot;&gt;Ahmad will be taking ownership of [the CC WordPress plugin&lt;/a&gt;,
      which simplifies the process of applying CC licenses to content created
      using the popular WordPress blogging platform. He will be updating it 
      to use the latest WordPress best practices, resolving open issues, and 
      adding new features like integrating with CC Search. Ahmad’s mentor is 
      our Core Systems Manager &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/author/timidcreativecommons-org/&quot;&gt;Timid Robot Zehta&lt;/a&gt;, backed up by Hugo Solar.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can follow the progress of this project through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/creativecommons-wordpress-plugin&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;code&gt;#cc-dev-wordpress&lt;/code&gt; channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col pt-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;ahmad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ahmad bilal&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;small class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Ahmad Bilal, credit: Usman C., CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dhruv Bhanushali&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am Dhruv Bhanushali, a Mumbai-based software developer recently
       graduated from IIT Roorkee. I started programming as a hobby some five 
      years ago and, having found my calling, am now am pursuing a career in 
      the field. I have worked on a lot of institute-level projects and am 
      excited to expand the reach of my code to a global scale with CC through
       GSoC. Apart from development, I am a huge music fan and keep my curated
       collection of music with me at all times. I also love to binge watch TV
       shows and movies, especially indie art _&lt;/em&gt;films._&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Dhruv will be working on an original project, CC Vocabulary, which is
       a collection of UI components that make it easy to develop Creative 
      Commons apps and services while ensuring a cohesive experience and 
      appearance across CC projects. These components will be able to be used 
      in sites built using modern JavaScript frameworks (specifically Vue.js) 
      as well as simpler websites built using WordPress. CC’s Web Developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/author/hugocreativecommons-org/&quot;&gt;Hugo Solar&lt;/a&gt; serves as primary mentor, with backup from Sophine Clachar.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can follow the progress of this project through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cc-vocabulary&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;code&gt;#gsoc-cc-vocabulary&lt;/code&gt; channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col pt-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;dhruv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dhruv bhanushali&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;small class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Dhruv Bhanushali, credit: Arpit Gupta, CC BY&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;María Belén Guaranda Cabezas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello! My name is María, and I am an undergraduate Computer 
      Science student from ESPOL, in Ecuador. I have worked for the past 2 
      years as a research assistant. I have worked in projects including 
      computer vision, the estimation of socio-economic indexes through CDRs 
      analysis, and a machine learning model with sensors data. During my 
      spare time, I like to watch animes and reading. I love sports! Specially
       soccer. I am also committed to environmental causes, and I am a huge 
      fan of cats and dogs (I have 4 and 1 respectively).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;María will be working on producing visualizations of the data 
      associated with more than 300 million works we have indexed in the CC 
      Catalog (which powers CC Search) and how that data is interconnected. 
      These visualizations will enable users to understand how much 
      CC-licensed content is available on the internet, which websites host 
      the most content, which CC licenses are used the most, and much more. 
      She will be mentored by our Data Engineer &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/author/sclachar/&quot;&gt;Sophine Clachar&lt;/a&gt; with backup from Breno Ferreira.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can follow the progress of this project through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog-dataviz&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;code&gt;#gsoc-cc-catalog-viz&lt;/code&gt; channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col pt-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;maria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;María Belén Guaranda Cabezas&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;small class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;María Belén Guaranda Cabezas, CC BY-NC-SA&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ari Madian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am an 18 year old, Seattle based, mostly self taught, Computer 
      Science student. I originally started programming by tinkering with 
      Python, and eventually moved into C# and the .NET framework, as well as 
      JS and some web development. I like Chai and Rooibos teas, volunteering 
      at my local food bank, and some occasional PC gaming, among other 
      things. I’m now working with Creative Commons on Google Summer of Code!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Ari will be working on creating a modern human-centered version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/choose/&quot;&gt;our CC license chooser tool&lt;/a&gt;, which is long overdue for an update. His work will focus on design and usability as well as code. CC’s Front End Engineer &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/author/brenoferreira/&quot;&gt;Breno Ferreira&lt;/a&gt; is the primary mentor for this project with support from Alden Page.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can follow the progress of this project through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cc-chooser&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;code&gt;#gsoc-license-chooser&lt;/code&gt; channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col pt-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ari Madian&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;small class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Ari Madian, credit: Ellen Madian, CC0&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mayank Nader&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am Mayank Nader, a sophomore Computer Science student from 
      India. Currently, my main area of interest is Python scripting, 
      JavaScript development, backend, and API development. I also like to 
      experiment with bash scripting and ricing and configuring my Linux 
      setup. Apart from that, I like listening to music and watching movies, 
      documentaries, and tv shows. I am very much inspired by Open Source and 
      try to contribute whenever I can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Mayank will be working on building a cross-platform browser plugin 
      that allows users to search CC-licensed works directly from the browser 
      and enable reuse of those works by providing easy image attribution 
      tools. Users will be able to find content to use without having to 
      switch to a new website. Mayank will be mentored by CC’s Software 
      Engineer &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/author/aldencreativecommons-org/&quot;&gt;Alden Page&lt;/a&gt; with support from Timid Robot Zehta.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can follow the progress of this project through the GitHub repo or on the #gsoc-browser-ext channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/6514859793973248/&quot;&gt;the Creative Commons organization page&lt;/a&gt;
       on Google Summer of Code site to see longer descriptions of the 
      projects. We welcome community input and feedback – you are the users of
       all these products and we’d love for you to be involved. So don’t 
      hesitate to join the project Slack channel or talk to us on GitHub or &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/community/&quot;&gt;our other community forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col pt-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;mayank.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mayank Nader&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;small class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Mayank Nader, credit: Rohit Motwani, CC BY&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2019/05/30/meet-ccs-2019-google-summer-of-code-students/&quot;&gt;on the primary Creative Commons blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-gsoc-accepted-students/">
    <title type="text">CC Google Summer of Code accepted students announced</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:6570016b-b89a-3f5a-9e6f-09a9c9d88f01</id>
    <updated>2019-05-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-gsoc-accepted-students/" />
    <author>
      <name>kgodey</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google Summer of Code has just announced the list of accepted students for 2019. We’d like to congratulate our accepted students Ahmad Bilal, Ari Madian, Dhruv Bhanushali, Maria Belen Guaranda, and Mayank Nader! Your mentors will be in touch with you with next steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reshuffled some of the mentors for the projects around (from our original &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/&quot;&gt;Project Ideas list&lt;/a&gt;) so that we could have a dedicated mentor for each project. I will be focusing on the responsibility of organization admin and supporting the projects however I can. Here's the final list of accepted proposals and mentors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CC WordPress Plugin&lt;/strong&gt; by Ahmed Bilal (mentor: Timid Robot Zehta, backup: Hugo Solar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New CC License Chooser&lt;/strong&gt; by Ari Madian (mentor: Breno Ferreira, backup: Alden Page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CC Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt; by dhruvkb (mentor: Hugo Solar, backup: Sophine Clachar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CC Catalog Visualization&lt;/strong&gt; by Maria Belen Guaranda (mentor: Sophine Clachar, backup: Breno Ferreira)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CC Browser Extension&lt;/strong&gt; by Mayank Nader (mentor: Alden Page, backup: Timid Robot Zehta)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/6514859793973248/#projects&quot;&gt;about the accepted proposals here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don’t lose heart if you were not accepted! We were amazed at the quality of proposals we got and we had to make some really tough decisions. We appreciate the hard work you put into your proposals and contributing to our code and we wish we could accept more proposals. We hope that you’ll stick around and &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/contributing-code/&quot;&gt;be part of the CC developer community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in working on one of our remaining &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/&quot;&gt;project ideas&lt;/a&gt; as a volunteer outside of Google Summer of Code, please reach out to me. These are all things that CC is invested in building and we can provide guidance. We are especially looking for help with &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/all/#supercharge-our-indexing-engine&quot;&gt;supercharging our search indexer&lt;/a&gt;, improving our tooling around license translations (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/all/#automated-link-checking&quot;&gt;automated license link checking&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/all/#cc-plugin-generic&quot;&gt;plugins for integrating CC Search with external creation platforms&lt;/a&gt;. If we have multiple volunteers for the same idea, we will ask them to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note about availability&lt;/em&gt;: all CC staff have very limited availability over the next week because of&lt;a href=&quot;https://summit.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt; CC Global Summit&lt;/a&gt; and CC is closed for most of the following week so we won’t be around at all then. Please be patient, we’ll respond to you as soon as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/open-source-at-cc-gs2019-pre-event/">
    <title type="text">Open Source at Creative Commons - 2019 Global Summit Event</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:b6919fc1-840a-3084-93ff-b2debfde5926</id>
    <updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/open-source-at-cc-gs2019-pre-event/" />
    <author>
      <name>sclachar</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons has been building free software for over a decade to support its mission of maximizing digital creativity, sharing, and innovation. We would love your assistance in creating and improving that software. Please join us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://summit.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Global Summit 2019&lt;/a&gt; in Lisbon, Portugal May 9-11 2019 where we will host a session entitled &lt;a href=&quot;https://ccglobalsummit2019lisbonportugal.sched.com/event/MiWW/open-source-at-creative-commons&quot;&gt;Open Source at Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the Creative Commons Engineering Team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss our primary projects and potential collaborations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network with the attendees to build a vibrant community of developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Information&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Date: Friday May 10, 2019 1:30pm - 2:25pm
&lt;br&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.museudooriente.pt/museuoriente/deli-ilhas.php&quot;&gt;New Delhi Room&lt;/a&gt;, 4th Floor, Museu do Oriente Av. Brasília 352, 1350-279 Lisboa, Portugal
&lt;br&gt;Moderator: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mzeinstra.nl/&quot;&gt;Maarten Zeinstra&lt;/a&gt; Chapter lead for Creative Commons Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to meeting you at this event and getting your feedback. If you would like to stay updated on our work, join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/a/creativecommons.org/forum/#!forum/cc-developers&quot;&gt;developer mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, the #creativecommons-dev IRC channel on &lt;a href=&quot;https://freenode.net/&quot;&gt;freenode&lt;/a&gt;, or the #cc-developers channel on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack-signup.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-search-out-of-beta/">
    <title type="text">CC Search is out of beta with 300M images and easier attribution</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:08054206-9702-389e-b5c0-ce707ce5884d</id>
    <updated>2019-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-search-out-of-beta/" />
    <author>
      <name>janeatcc</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;CC Search&lt;/a&gt; comes out of beta, with over 300 million images indexed from multiple collections, a major redesign, and faster, more relevant search. It’s the result of a huge amount of work from the engineering team at Creative Commons and our community of volunteer developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/entries/cc-search-out-of-beta/compressed-kittens-again.gif&quot; alt=&quot;cc-search-gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CC Search searches images across &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.creativecommons.org/about&quot;&gt;19 collections&lt;/a&gt; pulled from open APIs and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://commoncrawl.org/&quot;&gt;Common Crawl&lt;/a&gt; dataset, including cultural works from museums (the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Cleveland Museum of Art), graphic designs and art works (Behance, DeviantArt), photos from Flickr, and an initial set of CC0 3D designs from Thingiverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aesthetically, you’ll see some key changes — a cleaner home page, better navigation and filters, design alignment with creativecommons.org, streamlined attribution options, and clear channels for providing feedback on both the overall function of the site and on specific image reuses. It’s also now linked directly from the Creative Commons homepage as the default method to search for CC-licensed works, and replaces the old search portal (though that tool is still online &lt;a href=&quot;https://oldsearch.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, we improved search loading times and search phrase relevance, implemented analytics to better understand when and how the tools are used, and fixed many critical bugs our community helped us to identify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will continue to grow the number of images in our catalog, prioritizing key image collections such as Europeana and Wikimedia Commons. We also plan to index additional types of CC-licensed works, such as open textbooks and audio, later this year. While our ultimate goal remains the same (to provide access to all 1.4 billion works in the commons), we are initially focused on &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2019/03/19/cc-search/&quot;&gt;images that creators desire to reuse in meaningful ways&lt;/a&gt;, learning about how these images are reused in the wild, and incorporating that learning back into CC Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature-wise, we have specific deliverables for this quarter listed in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19yH2V5K4nzWgEXaZhkzD1egzrRayyDdxlzxZOTCm_pc/&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;, which includes advanced filters on the home page, the ability to browse collections without entering search terms, and improved accessibility and UX on mobile. In addition, we expect some work related to CC Search will be done by our Google Summer of Code students starting in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also presenting the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://sched.co/MhKv&quot;&gt;State of CC Search&lt;/a&gt;” at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://summit.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;CC Global Summit&lt;/a&gt; next month in Lisbon, Portugal, where we’ll host a global community discussion around desired features and collections for CC Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-involved&quot;&gt;Get involved&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is valuable, and we invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.creativecommons.org/feedback&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; what you would like to see improved. You can also join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.slack.com/messages/CCS9CF2JE/details/&quot;&gt;#cc-usability&lt;/a&gt; channel on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Slack#How_to_join_Slack&quot;&gt;CC Slack&lt;/a&gt; to keep up with new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of our code, including the code behind CC Search, is open source (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog-frontend/&quot;&gt;CC Search&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog-api&quot;&gt;CC Catalog API&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/cccatalog&quot;&gt;CC Catalog&lt;/a&gt;) and we &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/contributing-code/&quot;&gt;welcome community contribution&lt;/a&gt;. If you know how to code, we invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/&quot;&gt;join the growing CC developer community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CC Search is also made possible by a number of institutional and individual supporters and donors. Specifically, we would like to thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/about-peter-baldwin-lisbet-rausing/&quot;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; – a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;, and the Brin Wojcicki Foundation for their support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2019/04/30/cc-search-images/&quot;&gt;on the primary Creative Commons blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/open-development-with-saltstack/">
    <title type="text">Open Development with SaltStack</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:6dc70283-9d5a-3a76-bc8e-95cabae41752</id>
    <updated>2019-04-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/open-development-with-saltstack/" />
    <author>
      <name>TimidRobot</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am excited to publicize the open source repository for our SaltStack configuration: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/sre-salt-prime&quot;&gt;creativecommons/sre-salt-prime&lt;/a&gt;. This is a rare offering. Not many configuration management system repositories are open sourced. Read on for why this is important to me :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like open source software (&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/osd-annotated&quot;&gt;The Open Source Definition (Annotated) | Open Source Initiative&lt;/a&gt;). Over the years it has provided me with access and capabilities I would not normally be able to afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had very little money in college. My first computer was salvaged from a dumpster and ran entirely on open source software. I was once reduced to begging a few dollars to satisfy a museum's arbitrarily enforced &quot;suggested donation&quot;. Thankfully, open source image manipulation software powered many of my art projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the exception of typing class in high school and a few training sessions at work, I have never received any formal computer training. Instead, I was able to teach myself by using and investigating open source software. I have been able to determine exactly why open source software behaves the way it does by looking at the source code. It is instructive to be able to synthesize complex systems as a single user and participate in the same communities as SysAdmins using the same software with thousands or millions of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been gainfully employed in the technology sector for over a decade so the free cost of open source software is not as necessary to me. However, open source software remains very important. As a SysAdmin, I have repeatedly found open source communities to be a better resource for support than even the most expensive maintenance contract. The ability to make at-will modifications to a codebase can save project timelines, and seeing those modifications accepted upstream is deeply satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started at Creative Commons in the fall of 2018, I began using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(software)&quot;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt; full time. As part of my work on developing infrastructure as code at Creative Commons, I created a new open source repository for our SaltStack configuration: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativecommons/sre-salt-prime&quot;&gt;creativecommons/sre-salt-prime&lt;/a&gt;. While working on provisioning of AWS resources, I have had trouble finding examples. I learn best by example and I know I’m not alone. I hope opening this repository helps other Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) and Systems Administrators (SysAdmins).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect that working in the open will improve the quality of my work. Research has not only shown that people produce higher quality work when they expect it to be reviewed or shared, but also that open source allows others to provide criticism, feedback, and contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most of all, I hope to give back to the community. I hope it helps others learn when they do not have access to proprietary software at home, school, or work. I hope that my work in the open might lower the resources required to implement open source for others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-plus-gsoc-2019/">
    <title type="text">CC + Google Summer of Code 2019</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:e516bab4-2140-3384-9d82-d91e738b450c</id>
    <updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://creativecommons.github.io/blog/entries/cc-plus-gsoc-2019/" />
    <author>
      <name>kgodey</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/entries/cc-plus-gsoc-2019/cc-gsoc.png&quot; alt=&quot;CC + Google Summer of Code&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce that Creative Commons &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/6514859793973248/&quot;&gt;has been accepted as a mentor organization&lt;/a&gt; for the 2019 Google Summer of Code program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt; (GSoC) is a annual global program through which Google awards stipends to university students who write code for free and open-source software projects during their school break. CC has been a mentor organization for GSoC on seven previous occasions, but our last participation was in 2013, so we are glad to be reviving the tradition and hosting students again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve compiled &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/gsoc-2019/project-ideas/all/&quot;&gt;a list of project ideas&lt;/a&gt; for students to choose from when submitting their work proposal. There’s a lot of variety to choose from – adding features to CC Search, reviving older CC products, creating entirely new tools that increase the reach of CC licenses, figuring out ways to better present our legal and technical work, and more. There is definitely room for creativity – the project ideas are defined in broad terms, and students may also choose to submit a proposal for an original idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals of the CC engineering team this year is to build an active developer community around our projects. We’ve been writing free and open-source software for over a decade. Lately, we haven’t done the best job of enabling external developers to contribute to those projects. Hosting Google Summer of Code is our first step to change that for the better, and we’re also actively working on several other improvements to our code and processes, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.github.io/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Open Source&lt;/a&gt;, a hub for the CC developer community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making CC Search’s development more transparent. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/creativecommons/projects/7&quot;&gt;current sprint workload&lt;/a&gt; is already public and we’ll be releasing a roadmap soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General cleanup, documentation, and contribution guidelines for our projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A technical blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to stay updated on our work, join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/a/creativecommons.org/forum/#!forum/cc-developers&quot;&gt;brand new developer mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, the #creativecommons-dev IRC channel on &lt;a href=&quot;https://freenode.net/&quot;&gt;freenode&lt;/a&gt;, or the #cc-developers and #cc-gsoc channels on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack-signup.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;. And if you’re a student (or know a student), please consider submitting a Google Summer of Code proposal! It’s a great way to get an introduction to open-source, build real-world skills, work on interesting technical challenges, and help advance CC’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/2019/03/04/cc-google-summer-of-code-2019/&quot;&gt;on the primary Creative Commons blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
